escapemotions.com 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy | Escape Motions

Escape Motions, s.r.o. ("Escape Motions" or "we", “our” or "us") respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it through our compliance with this policy.

Escape Motions’ privacy policy covers the collection and use of personal information that may be collected by Escape Motions anytime you interact with us, such as when you visit our website, purchase and use an Escape Motions software product, contact a technical support, create an account in our Community center or sign up for an e-newsletter.

Personal information does not include information such as data, messages, text, graphics, images, photos, profiles, works of authorship and any other materials that have been posted on to the Escape Motions website. The use of this information is detailed in our [Terms of Use](https://www.escapemotions.com/terms-of-use).

We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. When we do we will update the “Last Updated” date. It is therefore important that you regularly review this Privacy Policy to ensure you are updated as to any changes.

#### 

Who Controls the Personal Information

All Personal Information collected is in the control of Escape Motions, s.r.o. in the event that Escape Motions, trading names and brands are subject to a change of ownership, the control and permissions that you have granted us with regard to your Personal Information will be transferred to the new owner. 

#### 

Information We Collect

### Information You Provide to Us

\- When you place an order with us for our software products, the information we collect may include your name, e-mail address, mailing address, billing address, shipping address and, if applicable, EU VAT number or other tax ID. We will also keep the details of your order and of its fulfillment. We never store your credit card information.

\- When you create account on our Community website, we may collect your username and e-mail address for your account.

\- When you sign up to receive our newsletters, we may collect your name and email address. By confirming the subscription you give us consent to send you occasional development updates and marketing communications. 

\- When you purchase or download a full version of an Escape Motions software we have a legitimate interest in sending you free updates, upgrade offers, new software releases and other news. If you change your mind, you can update your consent or email preferences at any time using the link provided at the bottom of each email you receive from us. If you do not want Escape Motions to contact you, you may “opt-out” at any time. You may “opt-out” by contacting Escape Motions Customer Service Department or by following the instructions included in the newsletter.

When we process your personal information for our legitimate interests, we make sure to consider and balance any potential impact on you, and your rights under data protection laws. Our legitimate interests do not automatically override your interests. We will not use your personal information for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you, unless we have your consent or those activities are otherwise required or permitted to by law. 

We collect your personal information because it assists us in delivering a high level of customer service. For example, your personal information helps us to keep you informed and up-to-date on the latest product updates and announcements as well as special offers that may be extended from time to time. 

### Information We Collect from our Software

We collect information when you use the Escape Motions software. When you use our software while your computer is connected to the Internet, we collect your registration details of the software, IP address, home-dir and MAC address of the computer, the version of the software and operating system. This is needed to ensure that the software is used in accordance with the software license agreement, to ensure the correct content is shown in the welcome screen of the applications and to identify a possible update notification.

Escape Motions software also collect crash report data anonymously.

### Cookies

Cookies are unique identifiers which are used to customize your website, mobile application or social media site experience. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent or notify you whenever you are sent a cookie. This gives you the chance to decide whether or not to accept the cookie. We may use cookies to collect your personal information and settings (language preferences, discounts, etc.). We use the information it provides to help us improve our website, mobile application, social media site and our services, and to provide our visitors with a better visit. Even without accepting a cookie you can still access all features on the site. There may, however, be limitations on your use of some site functions.

You can also choose not to accept the cookies by clicking “I disagree” button on the information window that pops up when you visit our website. Here you can also view our cookie declaration. 

#### 

How We Use Your Personal Information

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:   
\- To provide and improve our software products (your information helps us better respond to your individual problems and needs).  
\- To improve customer service (your information helps us effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs).  
\- To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.  
\- To send periodic emails about our own products that may be of interest to you (the email address you provide for order processing may be used to send you information and updates pertaining your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc.) and to keep you informed about all the news from our world.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving newsletters, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email. \- To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other feature.

We are not liable or responsible for the personally identifiable or other information you choose to submit in the community center of our website such as a forum, gallery or any other publicly accessible area of the site. 

#### 

How Long We Store Your Personal Information

If you purchase an Escape Motions software, download a full version of an Escape Motions software or subscribe to our newsletter, we will store your data for up to three years from the date of the latest purchase or from the day you subscribed. If you do choose to opt into our marketing, we will continue to contact you via email until you opt out. All of our emails contain an unsubscribe link.

#### 

Where We Store Personal Information

### Website Data

We store all personal data collected via our website and forum on secure servers administered by Exohosting, s.r.o., located in the Slovak republic (SK).

### Payments

We use Paypal (www.paypal.com) and Braintree (www.braintreepayments.com) payment gate ("Payment Gate") to process payments made via our store. After purchase we will pass your order details to Payment Gate to complete the transaction. Payment Gate will store some of your details as a reference against your transaction in case we need to process a refund or provide support, and for fraud prevention purposes. 

For more information, see Paypal’s and Braintree’s [Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full). 

### Email Marketing

Some of our email marketing is administered through Mailerlite (www.mailerlite.com), and we may store some of your information - including your name, email address and contact preferences - on a Mailerlite server. If you contact Mailerlite directly regarding your subscription to our email communications, Mailerlite may contact you directly; otherwise, they will never contact you. For more information, see Mailerlite’s [Privacy Policy](https://www.mailerlite.com/privacy-policy). 

#### 

Your Rights in Relation to Your Personal Information

### Right to Access

You can request and obtain details of the Personal Information we may hold about you by emailing us at support@escapemotions.com, or writing to us at the following address: 

Escape Motions, s.r.o.  
Teplická 24/134,   
92101 Piešťany  
Slovakia, Europe 

Please quote your name and email address. We would be grateful if you could also provide brief details of the information required as this will help us to accurately respond to your request. 

For the protection of all our customers, we will take all reasonable steps to confirm your identity before providing you with details of any Personal Information we may hold about you and we will aim to respond to such requests within 20 working days. 

### Right to Rectification

You may change your email address, password and other information for the Community center or the software by editing them in your Community account. If you find that any of the Personal Information we hold for you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request we update it by emailing support@escapemotions.com. Please include as much detail as possible regarding the changes you wish to make, as this will help us in dealing with your request.

### Your Right to Be Forgotten

You can request that we delete your Community account and any Personal Information we have collected from you by emailing us at support@escapemotions.com. Please provide your name and email address to help us with your request.

Please be aware that once deleted, your Community account will no longer be accessible and cannot be restored so you should ensure that any software or downloadable content you wish to keep are backed up before proceeding.

If you continue to use the Escape Motions software after deletion we will still need to store information such as your registration details of the software, IP address, homedir and mac address of the computer, the version of the software and operating system. This is needed to ensure that the software is used in accordance with the software licence agreement. 

### Right to Restrict Processing

You have the right to request that we restrict how we use your personal information.

### Right to Object

You have the right to object to the collection and use of your personal information at any time.

### Right to Data Portability

You have the right to obtain a copy of your personal information in a legible and compatible format such as Excel or Word.

### Right to Withdraw Consent

You have the right to withdraw your consent for us to use your personal information to send marketing information to you. Each marketing email that we send you will include a link which you can follow to opt-out of future marketing.

### Exercising Your Rights

You can exercise such rights by contacting us at support@escapemotions.com.

#### 

How We Protect Your Information

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you access your personal information. While we strive to protect the personal information you submit to us, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. As such, we cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our products and you do so at your own risk. Once your information has been received by Escape Motions, we will make our best effort to ensure the safety and security on our systems.

#### 

Disclosure of Your Information

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. However, we may release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect our or others rights, property or safety.

#### 

Children’s Information

We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to observe, participate in and/or monitor and guide their online activity. Escape Motions does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. We advise all children to first get their parents or guardians permission before creating an account for the Community page on our website.

#### 

Links to Other Websites

Our website, forum, gallery, social media sites and mobile applications may contain links to websites of third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those other websites.

#### 

Consent

By using our website and our software, you hereby consent to our privacy policy and agree to its terms.

#### 

Changes To Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page. This policy was last modified on 05/18/2018.

#### 

Contacting Escape Motions

To ask questions or comment about this privacy policy and our privacy practices, you may contact Escape Motions in the following ways:  
**Email:** [support@escapemotions.com](mailto:support@escapemotions.com)  
**Postal:** Escape Motions, Teplická 24/134, 92101 Piešťany, Slovakia, Europe
